Shailab Singh (1) Featured

Senior Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Devops, Requirement Gathering, Client Management, Web Development, Java, Python, C++, C, JIRA, Jenkins, Kubernetes. Bitbucket



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: HCL Avitas Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Developer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System

Analysis, Technical Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Client Management, Web

Development, Java, Python, C++, C, JIRA, Jenkins

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Full-Stack Developer with 4 years of combined IT functional experience and having good experience in Spring-boot, Vue.js, Deveops, and profound Knowledge of Algorithms and Data Structures. Currently seeking job opportunities to utilize my skills and abilities in a sector that offer professional growth as well as opportunities to learn and develop new perspectives

Work Experience

HCL Avitas as Software Engineer

Apr 2020 to Till Date

Designed and developed SSO and Admin Panel end to end using React and Spring-Boot. Connector Layer for HL7 inbound/outbound server.

Developed Container interface for the micro-fronted apps to interact with each other using ReactJs and Iframes.

Data Security for microservices using Asymmetric Signature with JWT token in Spring Boot.

Designed and Developed CD/CI pipeline using Bitbucket and AWS codedeploy for different projects.

Implemented an auto-scaling system on Kubernetes nodes for the project.

Developed Connector Layer for inbound and outbound traffic with HL7 server.

Designed and Developed keep-alive for User Productivity Aggregation using SpringBoot, Redis and ReactJs Client.

Peer to Peer Video Consult for Doctors using WebRTC and ReactJs.

Techbliss Digital as Senior Software Developer Sep 2019 to Apr 2020

Designed and developed LEGO GRID web-app using Vuejs, Vuex and Nuxt.js for Samsung. Spot Performer Award from Infinity Labs.

- Built Developer tools client side Sorting and Filtering for 1 Millions records that could take a maximum memory of 300MB in the Browser with IE 11 support with lazy load, full load and pagination support
- Used Vue scoped slot pattern to abstract the functionality to the higher components and write more maintainable and readable code for future.
- Fixed Spring-Boot Backend API's For Samsung Lego.
- Used NodeJs, SocketIO and Webterm to create a web based terminal with reverse proxy for Infinity Labs SDWAN

devices.

Conducted Developers' training for VueJs and Spring Boot

Project Striker as Full Stack Developer

Oct 2018 to Sep 2019

Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software according to the business objectives.

- Designed and developed effective web-app using peer to peer technologies in Vue.js, developed online coding compiler using spring and Shell-scripting Linux, developed centralized web-socket chat server using MongoDB, payment system using Stripe and Razor Pay.
- Integrated app-based solutions with databases, file systems, and cloud-based systems.
- Implemented stateless security protocols using JWT, Push Notifications using Firebase, elastic search as a 'Search Engine', Hybrid caching on redis database etc.
- Using Neo4j Graph Database Design for online Professional Networking platform, CI/CD using Bitbucket, Docker and Jenkins on AWS and GCP.
- Spring Aspect oriented programming for Notifications
- Managing a team of 4 developers with operations, priorities, and development goals
- Used Rest Controller in spring framework to create RESTful Web services and JSON objects for communication.
- Developed server side application to interact with database using Spring Boot and Hibernate.
- Applied Design patterns Singleton, Builder, Factory, Service locator etc.
- Developed POJOs for Data Model and made individual HBM records to delineate Java Objects with Relational database table

Duckart as Software Engineer

Aug 2017 to Sep 2018

Created reusable, testable, and efficient Java code using best programming structures, flowcharts and algorithms as well as assisted in designing and implementing spring modules to load data from various sources such as MySQL, Cassandra.

Developed and Created RESTful API's using Kotlin and Java for an e-commerce-based enterprise, developed a mobile web client to consume the API using Angular.js react.js HTML5/Materialize CSS

Wrote many unit tests, e2e tests, API tests in Spring Boot.

Added server push notifications using Web-sockets protocol

Involved in fixing code vulnerability issues, Involved in testing, bug fixing of the system and deployment as well as User Production support for the product.

Provide Maintenance and Enhancements activities for the product.

Developed APOC queries with spring data jpa for neo4j to create, retrieve and update data

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Amity School Engineering & technology in 2017

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Lucideus Certified Security Analyst

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Java, JavaScript, Python, C, C++	
Vue.Js, Angular, React, Spring-boot	
Kafka, Rabbitmq	
MySQL, Neo4j, Elastic search, MongoDB	
Docker, Jenkins, Jira	
AWS, GCP	
WINDOWS, LINUX	
Intellij Idea, WebStorm, PyCharm	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
hindi	Proficient			
english	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time